{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "1.Which institution prepares the National Health Account (NHA) estimates for India?",
            "options": [
                "WHO",
                "NITI Aayog",
                "AIIMS",
                "NHSRC"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "NHSRC"
        },
        {
            "question": "2.'Big Catch-up' Initiative is launched by which organization?",
            "options": [
                "IMF",
                "FAO",
                "WHO",
                "RBI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "WHO"
        },
        {
            "question": "3.How many Zero Shadow Day occurs in a year for places between Tropic of Cancer and the Tropicof Capricorn?",
            "options": [
                "One",
                "Two",
                "Three",
                "Four"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Two"
        },
        {
            "question": "4.As per the recently released NHA Estimates for India 2019-20, which is the share of Out-of-PocketExpenditure (OOPE) in total Health Expenditure (THE)?",
            "options": [
                "47.1%",
                "59.2%",
                "60.4%",
                "90.1%"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "47.1%"
        },
        {
            "question": "5.Spheroidal carbonaceous particle is a component of?",
            "options": [
                "Fly Ash",
                "Saw Dust",
                "Dry Ice",
                "Common Salt"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Fly Ash"
        },
        {
            "question": "6.As per a recent study, trees and crops endemic to which country have higher \u2018Air PollutionTolerance Index\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Brazil",
                "Chile",
                "Sri Lanka"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "India"
        },
        {
            "question": "7.Recently, the second deepest blue hole was discovered off the coast of Yucatan Peninsula in whichcountry?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Mexico",
                "Russia",
                "UAE"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mexico"
        },
        {
            "question": "8.\u2018Piarosoma arunachalensis\u2019, which was recently discovered, belongs to which species?",
            "options": [
                "Telangana",
                "Jharkhand",
                "Odisha",
                "West Bengal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "West Bengal"
        },
        {
            "question": "9. Which state/UT launched the ‘5T School Transformation Programme’?",
            "options": [
                "Moth",
                "Spider",
                "Turtle",
                "Snake"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Moth"
        },
        {
            "question": "10.Which institution released the \u2018Promoting Millets in Diets\u2019 Report?",
            "options": [
                "NABARD",
                "FCI",
                "NITI Aayog",
                "FSSAI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "NITI Aayog"
        },
        {
            "question": "11.Which company has been recently upgraded to the status of Navratna CPSE (in May 2023)?",
            "options": [
                "Airports Authority of India",
                "Rail Vikas Nigam Limited",
                "Hindustan Copper Limited",
                "Indian Railway Catering &amp; Tourism Corporation Limited"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Rail Vikas Nigam Limited"
        },
        {
            "question": "12.Which institution has launched the liquid nano Di-Ammonia Phosphate (DAP) in India?",
            "options": [
                "NITI Aayog",
                "NABARD",
                "IFFCO",
                "FCI"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "IFFCO"
        },
        {
            "question": "13.Which term denotes the \u2018extremely luminous and powerful active galactic nucleus\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Ultra- nucleus",
                "Quasar",
                "Ignition star",
                "Power-nucleus"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Quasar"
        },
        {
            "question": "14. Which city is the host of the ‘United Nations Permanent Forum on Indigenous Issues’?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "New York",
                "Sydney",
                "London"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "question": "15.As of 2023, what is the interest rate on deposits made under \u2018Mahila Samman Saving CertificateAccount\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "6.5 %",
                "7.5 %",
                "8.0 %",
                "8.5 %"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "7.5 %"
        },
        {
            "question": "16.\u2018Legal Debt Ceiling\u2019 is associated with which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "Japan",
                "Indonesia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "17.Which country has developed \u2018T-14 Armata battle tank\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Russia",
                "France",
                "Italy"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "18.Which country is supplying Mi-17 helicopter engines and auxiliary spare parts to Pakistan?",
            "options": [
                "China",
                "Pakistan",
                "Russia",
                "Ukraine"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Ukraine"
        },
        {
            "question": "19. India launched the 'NET Zero' Innovation Virtual Centre with which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "UK",
                "Australia",
                "South Korea"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "UK"
        },
        {
            "question": "20.What percentage of farmers are small farmers in India, as of 2023?",
            "options": [
                "65 %",
                "70 %",
                "80 %",
                "85 %"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "85 %"
        },
        {
            "question": "21.From which year, the \u2018IFRS 17\u2019 financial reporting standard became effective?",
            "options": [
                "2000",
                "2010",
                "2015",
                "2023"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "2023"
        },
        {
            "question": "22.\u2018Berenice Troglodytica\u2019, which was seen in the news, is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Egypt",
                "South Africa",
                "Sri Lanka",
                "USA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "23.Scientists have discovered a cave in which state to confirm that three droughts resulted indestruction of Harappa?",
            "options": [
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "Gujarat",
                "Assam",
                "Uttarakhand"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Uttarakhand"
        },
        {
            "question": "24.Which asteroid produces the annual Geminid meteor shower?",
            "options": [
                "Asteroid Phaethon",
                "Asteroid Ceres",
                "Asteroid Pallas",
                "Asteroid Vesta"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Asteroid Phaethon"
        },
        {
            "question": "25.Anji Bridge, which was seen in the news, is being built in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Arunachal Pradesh",
                "Punjab",
                "Sikkim"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
        },
        {
            "question": "26.Which is the most innovative state as per the \u2018National Manufacturing Innovation Survey (NMIS)2021-22\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "West Bengal",
                "Karnataka",
                "Maharashtra",
                "Telangana"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Karnataka"
        },
        {
            "question": "27.Voters Helpline App was introduced by the Election Commission for the seamless enrolment ofthe voters in which state?",
            "options": [
                "Assam",
                "Karnataka",
                "Kerala",
                "Goa"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Karnataka"
        },
        {
            "question": "28.What is the name of Indian Navy\u2019s 3rd indigenous stealth destroyer of the Project 15B class?",
            "options": [
                "INS Dhruv",
                "INS Imphal",
                "INS Kattabomman",
                "INS Vikram"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "INS Imphal"
        },
        {
            "question": "29.Majority of Gum Arabic is sourced from Sahel region, which runs through which country?",
            "options": [
                "Israel",
                "Sudan",
                "South Africa",
                "Ukraine"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Sudan"
        },
        {
            "question": "30.Which country organises the annual \u2018Free Land Camp\u2019 for indigenous people?",
            "options": [
                "Brazil",
                "South Africa",
                "USA",
                "Australia"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "31.\u2018Muthamizh Arignar Dr. Kalaignar Pen Monument\u2019 is to be built in the memory of which leader?",
            "options": [
                "C.N Anna Durai",
                "Periyar E.V.Ramasamy",
                "M Karunanidhi",
                "M G Ramachandran"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "M Karunanidhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "32.Which country has recently banned \u2018Dwarf Bull-fighting\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Spain",
                "USA",
                "China",
                "South Korea"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "33.The \u2018National Conference of National Police Mission (NPM)\u2019 is organised in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "New Delhi",
                "Maharashtra",
                "Punjab",
                "Goa"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "34.What is the objective of the \u2018Jagananna Chebudam scheme\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Grievance Redressal",
                "Scholarship to Students",
                "Financial Aid to Women",
                "Financial Aid to Trans-gender people"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Grievance Redressal"
        },
        {
            "question": "35.Which state\/UT launched the \u2018Ladli Bahna Yojana\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "Gujarat",
                "Madhya Pradesh",
                "Maharashtra",
                "Goa"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Madhya Pradesh"
        },
        {
            "question": "36.Who is the first Indian to complete the Golden Globe Race?",
            "options": [
                "Avani Chaturvedi",
                "Abhilash Tomy",
                "Bhawana Kanth",
                "Mohana Singh Jitarwal"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Abhilash Tomy"
        },
        {
            "question": "37.Abdulla Aboobacker, who was seen in the news recently, plays which sports?",
            "options": [
                "Triple Jump",
                "Javelin Throw",
                "Swimming",
                "Chess"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Triple Jump"
        },
        {
            "question": "37.Abdulla Aboobacker, who was seen in the news recently, plays which sports?",
            "options": [
                "Triple Jump",
                "Javelin Throw",
                "Swimming",
                "Chess"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Triple Jump"
        },
        {
            "question": "39.Which state\/UT launched the \u2018Adarsha Colony initiative\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "West Bengal",
                "Assam",
                "Odisha",
                "Jharkhand"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Odisha"
        },
        {
            "question": "40.Which country adopted the \u2018Basic Plan on Ocean Policy\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "Japan",
                "Indonesia",
                "India"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Japan"
        },
        {
            "question": "41.What is the name of the company owned by a group of individuals who pledge to pay in case thecompany is wound up?",
            "options": [
                "Company limited by guarantee",
                "Private Limited Company",
                "One Person Company",
                "Limited Liability Company (LLC)"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Company limited by guarantee"
        },
        {
            "question": "42.Johnson Space Center's Thermal Vacuum Chamber is located in which country?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "USA",
                "Australia",
                "Israel"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "43.Which institution released the \u2018Chief Economists Outlook Report 2023\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "IMF",
                "ADB",
                "WEF",
                "AIIB"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "WEF"
        },
        {
            "question": "44.Ocean Census Project is aimed at identifying and recording how many species?",
            "options": [
                "1000",
                "10,000",
                "100,000",
                "1,000,000"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "100,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "45.Which is the governing body of the Department of Atomic Energy in India?",
            "options": [
                "Atomic Energy Commission of India",
                "NITI Aayog",
                "Department of Space",
                "DRDO"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Atomic Energy Commission of India"
        },
        {
            "question": "46.\u2018All India Vedic Science Conference\u2019 was inaugurated in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Maharashtra",
                "New Delhi",
                "Gujarat",
                "Assam"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "47.What is the name of world\u2019s first robotic check-in assistant, that was launched by Emirates?",
            "options": [
                "Sara",
                "Kiwi",
                "Siri",
                "Rini"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Sara"
        },
        {
            "question": "48.\u2018Sinthan Festival\u2019 was organised in which state\/UT?",
            "options": [
                "Jammu and Kashmir",
                "Assam",
                "West Bengal",
                "Karnataka"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Jammu and Kashmir"
        },
        {
            "question": "49.Which institution released the \u2018Business Ready (B-READY) project?",
            "options": [
                "IMF",
                "World Bank",
                "WEF",
                "ADB"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "World Bank"
        },
        {
            "question": "50.Which country hosted the \u2018ASEAN India Maritime Exercise (AIME-2023)\u2019?",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Singapore",
                "Thailand",
                "Myanmar"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Singapore"
        }
    ]
}